<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Olivia Cooper</title>
    <link>https://0cooper.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://0cooper.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Olivia Cooper</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://0cooper.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Olivia Cooper</title>
      <link>https://0cooper.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>RUBIES: JWST/NIRSpec resolves evolutionary phases of dusty star-forming galaxies at  z∼2</title>
      <link>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/rubies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/rubies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dearth of high quality spectroscopy of dusty star-forming galaxies (DSFGs) &amp;ndash; the main drivers of the assembly of dust and stellar mass at the peak of activity in the Universe &amp;ndash; greatly hinders our ability to interpret their physical processes and evolutionary pathways. We present JWST/NIRSpec observations from RUBIES of four submillimeter-selected, ALMA-detected DSFGs at cosmic noon, z∼2.3−2.7. While photometry uniformly suggests vigorous ongoing star formation for the entire sample in line with canonical DSFGs, the spectra differ: one source has spectroscopic evidence of an evolved stellar population, indicating a recent transition to a post-starburst phase, while the remainder show strong spectroscopic signatures of ongoing starbursts. All four galaxies are infrared-luminous (log10LIR/L⊙ &amp;gt;12.4), massive (log10M⋆/M⊙ &amp;gt;11), and very dust-obscured (AV∼3−4 ABmag). Leveraging detections of multiple Balmer and Paschen lines, we derive an optical attenuation curve consistent with Calzetti overall, yet an optical extinction ratio RV∼2.5, potentially indicating smaller dust grains or differences in star-dust geometry. This case study provides some of the first detailed spectroscopic evidence that the DSFGs encompass a heterogeneous sample spanning a range of star formation properties and evolutionary stages, and illustrates the advantages of synergistic JWST and ALMA analysis of DSFGs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Web Epoch of Reionization Lyman-alpha Survey (WERLS). I. MOSFIRE Spectroscopy of z ∼ 7–8 Lyman-alpha Emitters</title>
      <link>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/werls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/werls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We present the first results from the Web Epoch of Reionization Lyα Survey (WERLS), a spectroscopic survey of Lyα emission using Keck I/MOSFIRE and LRIS. WERLS targets bright (J &amp;lt; 26) galaxy candidates with photometric redshifts of 5.5 ≲ z ≲ 8 selected from pre-JWST imaging embedded in the Epoch of Reionization (EoR) within three JWST deep fields: CEERS, PRIMER, and COSMOS-Web. Here, we report 11 z ∼ 7–8 Lyα emitters (LAEs; three secure and eight tentative candidates) detected in the first five nights of WERLS MOSFIRE data. We estimate our observed LAE yield is ∼13%, which is broadly consistent with expectations assuming some loss from redshift uncertainty, contamination from sky OH lines, and that the Universe is approximately half-ionized at this epoch, whereby observable Lyα emission is unlikely for galaxies embedded in a neutral intergalactic medium. Our targets are selected to be UV-bright, and span a range of absolute UV magnitudes with −23.1 &amp;lt; MUV &amp;lt; −19.8. With two LAEs detected at z = 7.68, we also consider the possibility of an ionized bubble at this redshift. Future synergistic Keck+JWST efforts will provide a powerful tool for pinpointing beacons of reionization and mapping the large-scale distribution of mass relative to the ionization state of the Universe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching Far and Long. I. Pilot ALMA 2 mm Follow-up of Bright Dusty Galaxies as a Redshift Filter TEST</title>
      <link>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/2mm-ssa22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/2mm-ssa22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A complete census of dusty star-forming galaxies (DSFGs) at early epochs is necessary to constrain the obscured contribution to the cosmic star formation rate density (CSFRD); however, DSFGs beyond z ~ 4 are both rare and hard to identify from photometric data alone due to degeneracies in submillimeter photometry with redshift. Here, we present a pilot study obtaining follow-up Atacama Large Millimeter Array (ALMA) 2 mm observations of a complete sample of 39 850 μm-bright dusty galaxies in the SSA22 field. Empirical modeling suggests 2 mm imaging of existing samples of DSFGs selected at 850 μm-1 mm can quickly and easily isolate the ‘‘needle in a haystack’’ DSFGs that sit at z &amp;gt; 4 or beyond. Combining archival submillimeter imaging with our measured ALMA 2 mm photometry (1σ ~ 0.08 mJy beam-1 rms), we characterize the galaxies’ IR spectral energy distributions (SEDs) and use them to constrain redshifts. With available redshift constraints fit via the combination of six submillimeter bands, we identify 6/39 high-z candidates each with &amp;gt;50% likelihood to sit at z &amp;gt; 4, and find a positive correlation between redshift and 2 mm flux density. Specifically, our models suggest the addition of 2 mm to a moderately constrained IR SED will improve the accuracy of a millimeter-derived redshift from Δz/(1 + z) = 0.3 to Δz/(1 + z) = 0.2. Our IR SED characterizations provide evidence for relatively high-emissivity spectral indices (&amp;lt;β&amp;gt; = 2.4 ± 0.3) in the sample. We measure that especially bright (S 850μ m &amp;gt; 5.55 mJy) DSFGs contribute ~10% to the cosmic-averaged CSFRD from 2 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 5, confirming findings from previous work with similar samples.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum gaps for adult climate literacy</title>
      <link>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/cooper-curriculum-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/cooper-curriculum-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conservation scientists need to advance climate literacy so that
people understand how climate affects all of life, acquire the skills
to communicate about climate change, and become aware of ways to
increase local resiliency. We examined syllabus content for 74 general
climate change courses taught at the undergraduate college‐level to
investigate the scope and extent to which these climate change courses
include key topics to advance climate literacy. By analyzing the
textual data, we discovered most courses had a strong focus on
biogeophysical science and only 8.8 and 9.4% of the terms that
occurred in this sample were connected to climate change solutions and
communication, respectively. The fine category “Organisms,” which
includes terms for specific animals such as “jellyfish” and “urchin”
and related terms like “species”, was only observed in 26% of the
syllabi; and the term “biodiversity” was mentioned seven times,
“extinction” four times, and “animal” was mentioned two times across
all 74 syllabi. This reveals a potential gap in addressing the impacts
of climate change on biodiversity, and the role of some species in
regulating climate. We recommend educators include a broader array of
inter‐disciplinary topics, place‐based information, communication
strategies, and mitigation and adaptation solutions to bridge the gap
between climate science, literacy, and action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out my blog post summary of the article
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ucanr.edu/blogs/blogcore/postdetail.cfm?postnum=31186&amp;amp;sharing=yes&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
