<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 | Olivia Cooper</title>
    <link>https://0cooper.github.io/publication_types/2/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://0cooper.github.io/publication_types/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://0cooper.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://0cooper.github.io/publication_types/2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching Far and Long. I. Pilot ALMA 2 mm Follow-up of Bright Dusty Galaxies as a Redshift Filter</title>
      <link>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/2mm-ssa22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/2mm-ssa22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A complete census of dusty star-forming galaxies (DSFGs) at early epochs is necessary to constrain the obscured contribution to the cosmic star formation rate density (CSFRD); however, DSFGs beyond z ~ 4 are both rare and hard to identify from photometric data alone due to degeneracies in submillimeter photometry with redshift. Here, we present a pilot study obtaining follow-up Atacama Large Millimeter Array (ALMA) 2 mm observations of a complete sample of 39 850 μm-bright dusty galaxies in the SSA22 field. Empirical modeling suggests 2 mm imaging of existing samples of DSFGs selected at 850 μm-1 mm can quickly and easily isolate the ‘‘needle in a haystack’’ DSFGs that sit at z &amp;gt; 4 or beyond. Combining archival submillimeter imaging with our measured ALMA 2 mm photometry (1σ ~ 0.08 mJy beam-1 rms), we characterize the galaxies’ IR spectral energy distributions (SEDs) and use them to constrain redshifts. With available redshift constraints fit via the combination of six submillimeter bands, we identify 6/39 high-z candidates each with &amp;gt;50% likelihood to sit at z &amp;gt; 4, and find a positive correlation between redshift and 2 mm flux density. Specifically, our models suggest the addition of 2 mm to a moderately constrained IR SED will improve the accuracy of a millimeter-derived redshift from Δz/(1 + z) = 0.3 to Δz/(1 + z) = 0.2. Our IR SED characterizations provide evidence for relatively high-emissivity spectral indices (&amp;lt;β&amp;gt; = 2.4 ± 0.3) in the sample. We measure that especially bright (S 850μ m &amp;gt; 5.55 mJy) DSFGs contribute ~10% to the cosmic-averaged CSFRD from 2 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 5, confirming findings from previous work with similar samples.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum gaps for adult climate literacy</title>
      <link>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/cooper-curriculum-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/cooper-curriculum-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
