<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adina Merenlender | Olivia Cooper</title>
    <link>https://0cooper.github.io/authors/adina-merenlender/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://0cooper.github.io/authors/adina-merenlender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Adina Merenlender</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://0cooper.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Adina Merenlender</title>
      <link>https://0cooper.github.io/authors/adina-merenlender/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum gaps for adult climate literacy</title>
      <link>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/cooper-curriculum-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://0cooper.github.io/publication/cooper-curriculum-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conservation scientists need to advance climate literacy so that
people understand how climate affects all of life, acquire the skills
to communicate about climate change, and become aware of ways to
increase local resiliency. We examined syllabus content for 74 general
climate change courses taught at the undergraduate college‐level to
investigate the scope and extent to which these climate change courses
include key topics to advance climate literacy. By analyzing the
textual data, we discovered most courses had a strong focus on
biogeophysical science and only 8.8 and 9.4% of the terms that
occurred in this sample were connected to climate change solutions and
communication, respectively. The fine category “Organisms,” which
includes terms for specific animals such as “jellyfish” and “urchin”
and related terms like “species”, was only observed in 26% of the
syllabi; and the term “biodiversity” was mentioned seven times,
“extinction” four times, and “animal” was mentioned two times across
all 74 syllabi. This reveals a potential gap in addressing the impacts
of climate change on biodiversity, and the role of some species in
regulating climate. We recommend educators include a broader array of
inter‐disciplinary topics, place‐based information, communication
strategies, and mitigation and adaptation solutions to bridge the gap
between climate science, literacy, and action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out my blog post summary of the article
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ucanr.edu/blogs/blogcore/postdetail.cfm?postnum=31186&amp;amp;sharing=yes&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
